

Leonardo Calderon J.

Software Engineer STEM Professor

<u>leocjj.tech/</u> +573165237608

PROFILE

Software Engineer with experience also as a Project Manager and STEM Professor, onsite and remotely, goal-oriented, with skills and strengths to enhance teams, processes, and businesses.

Interested in high-level language applications especially Python, Data Analysis and become a Machine Learning expert and Data Scientist.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- VS Code, Jupyter, PyCharm.
- C, Python, Numpy, Pandas, R.
- HTML, Javascript, CSS, PHP, AJAX, Flask, Django.
- AWS Lambda, API Gateway, S3.
- Shell, Git/GitHub.
- REST API, MySQL.
- MS Sharepoint, Excel, Project.
- Linux, Windows, Arduino, Raspberry.
- Mathematics, Statistics, Physics.
- Entrepreneurship.
- Investment projects formulation and evaluation.
- Financial and stock market fundamentals.

LANGUAGES

Spanish: native

• English: <u>76/100 (C2)</u>

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Skillshare

Software Engineer Backend AWS Lambda with Python 2020

- Launched an online translation web service.
- Created an AWS API Gateway and lambda back-end with Python.
- Improved front-end with online translation to +8 languages.

Veos Smart Vending

Software Engineer IoT with Google Cloud and Python 2020

- Researched protocols for IoT (Raspberry) telemetry.
- Tested MQTT protocol using Google Cloud Platform.
- Reduced communication package size consumption by 80%.

RedSST.com Software Engineer Full Stack

2019

- Implemented HTML5, CCS, JS, PHP, AJAX, Python, and MySQL.
- Launched a web site for the community of people in Safety.

Univalle Software Engineer

2018

Researched science projects with Arduino, Python, and NumPy.

UNIAJC Professor in STEM subjects 2016-Present

- Developed +8 STEM subjects for Engineer careers using Project Based Learning and active methodologies.
- Reorganized remote teaching tools to migrate 6 courses.

K&L Consultores SAS Project Manager 2016-Present

- Implemented projects, Safety, and Software Engineering. Designed, innovated, built, and deployed industrial systems and training.
- Developed database for documentation, inventory, and audit processes.

Baxter Software Validation Engineer May 2014 – Jul 2015

 Completed successfully a 2-years project as Software validation lead for IT compliance global team.

Baxter Senior Engineer

May 2007 - Apr 2015

- Developed Safety program for the Cali facility.
- Achieved status as a regional auditor and consultant.
- Completed investment projects of +100k USD per year.

Pfizer Junior engineer Jul 2003 – Dec 2004

- Created a Commissioning & Qualification (C&Q) program.
- Improved manufacturing projects of +2M USD using C&Q program.

CORE STRENGTHS

- Leadership
- Change management
- Problem Solver
- Teamwork
- Strategic planning
- Process management
- Critical thinking
- Agile-Scrum focus

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

- Outdoor walks
- Speed-skating
- Animals
- Science books

CONTACT DETAILS

- (+57) 3165237608
- Cali, Colombia (willing to relocate)
- ▶ leonardocj@gmail.com
- github.com/leocji
- <u>twitter.com/leoci</u>
- ► linkedin.com/in/leonardoci

EDUCATION

Full-stack software engineering

Holberton School

- Peer-learning, project-guided, full-stack software engineering.
- School from San Francisco focused on projects Low-level (C), High-level (Python), Front-end, Back-end & DevOps.

Master degree in Mathematics

2020

2020

Universidad Tecnológica de Pereira

- Algebra, Analysis, Calculus, Linear Algebra, Stats.
- Advanced teaching techniques.

Project management Specialization

2011

Universidad Libre. Colombia

- PMI standard based on PMBOK.
- Thesis: improvement of a Project Management Office.

Bachelor's degree in Engineering

2003

Universidad Autónoma de Occidente

- Graduated **summa cum laude.** Grade: 4.7/5.0.
 - Thesis: physics remote laboratory. Java client-server model.
 - Teacher assistance for mathematics.

PROFESSIONAL REFERENCES

Andrés Barreto, @andresbarreto. Investor @firstrockvc @socialatomv. Board @holbertoncol @enterco @coderiseorg +1 (650) 488-3054

Silvia Guzmán, Holberton School Campus Manager @SilviaGuzmanAr1 (+57) 315-616-3932

Andres Rojas, Software Engineer, and Education Lead Entrepreneur, CEO and Co-founder of GeoEstate.co @andreserojasi (+57) 320-773-2422

Walter Donneys, Director of Industrial Engineer at UNIAJC. wdonneys@admon.uniajc.edu.co (+57) 315-573-9316